<resources>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id">ca-app-pub-1709471374341277/5065944346</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id_animals">ca-app-pub-1709471374341277/6988709146</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id_general">ca-app-pub-1709471374341277/8465442346</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id_plants">ca-app-pub-1709471374341277/9942175547</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id_places">ca-app-pub-1709471374341277/2418908748</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id_history">ca-app-pub-1709471374341277/3895641941</string>
    <string name="banner_ad_unit_id_coyote">ca-app-pub-1709471374341277/5372375144</string>

    <string name="app_name">funfactstahoe</string>
    <string name="title_activity_test">TestActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hilltop_lodge">hilltop_lodgeActivity</string>

    <string name="bald_eagle">Bald Eagle This eagle can occasionally be seen during the winter months at Lake Tahoe. The majestic adult Bald Eagle, with a wing span reaching seven feet, can easily be identified because of its white head and tail. Often mistaken for an eagle, the Osprey is a summer resident of the Basin. It is sometimes referred to as a Fish Hawk because it feeds only on fish.</string>
    <string name="bear">One of Tahoe’s most loved and well-known wildlife species is its black bears. There are an estimated 25,000 to 35,000 black bears in California and Nevada. Males are much larger than females and can weigh up to 500 pounds, although average weight Is about 300 pounds. Black bears can sprint up to 35 mph and they are strong swimmers and great tree climbers. A typical wild bear diet consists of berries, plants, nuts, roots, honey, honeycomb, insects, larvae, carrion, and small mammals. Each summer, newspapers are filled with stories of bears breaking into houses, and being unnecessarily killed by wildlife officials. To prevent this please NEVER have food in your tent, sleeping bag or car. Keep sleeping bags, tents and sleeping areas free of food and beverage odors. Do not sleep In clothes that smell like food, or that were worn while cooking. Store food in bear proof canisters or bear proof lockers. The trunk of your car and coolers are not bear-proof! Do not leave out food, stored drinks. The smell will attract bears. Clean everything after preparing a meal.</string>
    <string name="beaver">American Beavers have prospered building their dams and lodges in the many lakes and rivers of the Lake Tahoe area. American Beavers subsist mostly on the inner bark of cottonwood, aspen, and willows.</string>
    <string name="combstock">Lake tahoe became the accessus area for large timber this was due to the ophir mine during the comstock era. The mine first to encounter problems with the loose, crumbly ore body. At a depth of 50 feet, the tunnel was 10 to 12 feet wide, but by the time it reached the 180-foot level, it was 40 to 50 feet wide. Local pine was limited, and timber from the short, scrubby trees, spliced together with iron bolts and bars, could not withstand the pressure of the constantly shifting earth. Soon the mine was too unsafe to operate. Until in 1860 a German engineer, Philip Deidesheimer, was brought in to solve the problem. Inspired by the honeybee’s comb, he invented square-set timbering, a framing system that used interlocking rectangular timber sets to support the unstable rocks. James W. Haines is commonly credited with constructing the first successful V-shaped flume on the Sierra, in 1867. “There were often sawmills at the staging areas,” sending large volumes of logs down the flumes. It is estimated that over 80 percent of the Basin\'s forests were clear cut during the Comstock era during the 1860s. Loggers constructed gravitation flumes that operated without the aid of water in some very steep places. The logs slid down straight chutes faster than speeding trains. The first V-flume associated with Haines ran 32.5 miles from Alpine County, California, to Empire City, Nevada, and connected there via rail to the Comstock. The new technology was quickly adopted by firms profiting from the Comstock Lode market for timber. In his 1879–1880 report, the surveyor general for Nevada reported ten major flumes with a length of 80 miles transporting 33.3 million board feet of lumber and 171,000 cords of wood.</string>
    <string name="Coyote">If any animal can be said to typify the wild character of the west, it certainly would be the Coyote. The Coyote is a very curious animal and often lives close to humans. They usually hunt at night for small rodents. Coyotes are often seen near highways in the Tahoe Basin.</string>
    <string name="goldFish">Enormous goldfish can be found in Lake Tahoe. While the goldfish may seem innocent and beautiful in a glass fish bowl, they like other invasive species can wreak havoc on the lake’s natural ecosystem. Invasive species can harm native fish by destroying their habitat, preying on them directly or interfering with their food source. In the case of the giant goldfish, researchers believe they may actually be harming lake clarity by fueling algae growth with their waste.</string>
    <string name="goldeneagle">Golden Eagle are brown with tawny on the back of the head and neck. Juveniles have white patches at base of primaries, white tail with a distinct dark terminal band. It takes four years to acquire adult plumage. The golden eagle is a solitary bird, which can be found in remote areas.</string>
    <string name="hairywoodpeckers">Hairy Woodpeckers are usually found in mature mixed woods. This robin-sized bird can be recognized by the vertical white stripe on its black back, and its long bill. Like most woodpeckers the Hairy Woodpecker feeds on tree boring insects, berries, acorns and sap. These woodpeckers are very often confused with Downy Woodpeckers which have the same markings but are smaller in size and have a shorter bill. \n\n Source\n https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Hairy_Woodpecker/id</string>
    <string name="goldenmantled">Golden Mantled Ground Squirrel Often confused with the chipmunk, the Golden-mantled Ground Squirrel has a broad white stripe-bordered back, but is larger than any chipmunk. Also the stripes do not extend up to the cheeks and face as they do on the chipmunk. Its diet is variable, including nuts, seeds, grasses, fruits and carrion.</string>
    <string name="hilltop">Truckee reportedly had one of the nation\'s first mechanized ski lifts at the site of the Hilltop Lodge. There were possibly two rope tows and a Poma lift, which was installed in 1954. At the same location, there was a ski jump constructed during the early 1900s that was designed by Lars Haugen, a seven time Olympic ski jumping champion.</string>
    <string name="jefferyPine">Jeffrey pine (Pinus jeffreyi) was discovered in 1852 in the Shasta Valley of California by John Jeffrey, a Scottish botanical explorer. The Jeffrey is the dominant pine tree species the Lake Tahoe Basin. Jeffrey pine is a large coniferous evergreen tree, reaching 25 to 40 m (82 to 131 ft) tall, and rarely up to 53 m (174 ft) tall. The Jeffrey is very closely related to ponderosa pine and is similar in appearance. One way to distinguish between them is by their cones. Each has barbs at the end of the scales. The sharp Jeffrey pine cone scale barbs point inward, so the cone feels smooth to the palm of one\'s hand when rubbed down the cone. Ponderosa pine cone scale barbs point outward, so feel sharp and prickly to the palm of one\'s hands. The Jeffrey can be recognized by its tall, straight massive trunk and relatively long, symmetrical crown. The bark is generally reddish brown with narrow plates between deep fissures. Jeffrey pine thrives in comparatively harsh environments. Requires longer cold exposure for leader growth in spring. Because Jeffrey pine is especially cold hardy tolerant of drought and adapted to short growing seasons, it competes well and typically dominates other conifers. They may live up to 400 to 500 years and on the best sites can reach an impressive size. Several general accounts state that Jeffrey pines 1.2 to 1.8 m (4 to 6 ft) in diameter and 52 to 61 m (170 to 200 ft) tall. The largest known survivor is on the Stanislaus National Forest in the western Sierra Nevada and measures 229 cm (90 in) in diameter and 53 m (175 ft) tall (36). \n\n Source\nhttp://www.na.fs.fed.us/pubs/silvics_manual/Volume_1/pinus/jeffreyi.htm</string>
    <string name="johnfreemont">The first recorded discovery of Lake Tahoe by white explorers was on Feb. 14, 1844, when John Charles Frémont and Charles Preuss spotted the lake from atop Red Lake Peak. John named the lake “Mountain Lake” and then called it “L. Bonpland,” in honor of French botanist Aimé Jacques Alexandre Bonpland. The name was changed to Lake Bigler in 1857 in honor of Calif. Gov. John Bigler. The lake was renamed Tahoe in 1945.</string>
    <string name="kokanee">Tahoe’s most famous non-native fish is its kokanee, which spawn in Taylor Creek every fall. They were accidentally introduced into Lake Tahoe in 1944 from holding ponds that overflowed at the old Tahoe City Fish Hatchery. Three years after their accidental introduction the salmon returned to Tahoe City to spawn. Knowing that the Kokanee would survive in Lake Tahoe, it was decided that the hatchery would do a yearly planting of fingerlings in the tributary streams. These plantings began in 1949. Today, California Department of Fish and Game continues to plant fingerlings in Taylor Creek to maintain a healthy population. In preparation for their spawning run, Kokanee salmon turn bright red. Bears at Lake Tahoe are attracted to the Kokanee salmon spawning in Taylor Creek. \n\n Source\n http://www.tahoekidsguide.com/Kokanee_Salmon_in_Tahoe.html</string>
    <string name="lohontancutthroat">The Lahontan Cutthroat Trout was the dominant fish in the Lake Tahoe Basin. Large and long-lived, they can grow to an impressive 50 inches in length and weigh up to 40 pounds. In 1844, there were 11 lake dwelling populations of Lahontan cutthroat trout and 400 to 600 steam dwelling populations in over 3,600 miles of streams within the major basins of Lake Lahontan. Lahontan cutthroat trout currently only occupy between 123 to 129 streams within the Lahontan basin and 32 to 34 streams are outside the basin, totaling approximately 482 miles of occupied habitat. The species is also found in five lakes, including two small populations in Summit and Independence Lakes. Self-sustaining populations of the species occur in 10 percent of the historic stream habitats and 0.4 percent of the historic lake habitats. As subpopulations of the species become isolated due to physical and biological fragmentation, migration rates decrease, thus the entire population may move incrementally toward extinction. The Native people of Lake Tahoe once depended heavily on the trout for their livelihood.</string>
    <string name="lakeclarity">The clarity of Lake Tahoe was first made famous by Mark Twain in the 1880s. Tragically, the pristine clarity of Lake Tahoe as experienced by early visitors is no more. Consistent scientific measurements of water clarity started in 1968. At that point, one could see a white disk submerged to a depth of 106 feet. Tahoe is still clear today in some places objects can be seen to depths of over 70 feet. This is a dramatic drop from the measurement in 1968. Lake Tahoe is losing about one foot of water clarity per year. Lake Tahoe is experiencing a phenomenon known as cultural eutrophication. The human impact has created excessive algal growth due to excessive nutrient levels. Nitrogen and phosphorus from automobile emissions and urban and forested areas act like fertilizer to accelerate algal growth. The fine sediments found are tiny, ground up particles much smaller than the width of a human hair. These fine sediments enter the lake from roadways and urban areas. Rather than falling to the bottom of the lake, fine sediments remain suspended in the water column, making the shoreline areas appear murky and brown.\n\n Source\n https://keeptahoeblue.org/protect/water/\n http://news.ucdavis.edu/search/news_detail.lasso?id=11171</string>
    <string name="laketahoecover">Summer is the most popular time to visit Lake Tahoe. Thanks to the pleasant temperatures that hover in the low 80’s °F combined with low humidity. At the night, some outerwear is often needed as temperatures typically dip down in the mid 40’s °F. The most popular summer activities include boating, biking, hiking, swimming, paddle boarding, kayaking, rock climbing, and just dozing on the beach. Prepare yourself for large crowds on any given weekend. Thus make sure you book accommodations at least three months in advance to ensure availability.</string>
    <string name="laketahoewinter">Lake Tahoe\’s water temperature remains a constant 39 degrees Fahrenheit below 600 feet. During the winter months, the average high air temperature is in the mid 40\’s °F. However, the main body of Lake Tahoe does not freeze due to the massive amount of water compared to its relative surface area. At lake level, the annual snowfall averages 125 inches. At the alpine skiing elevations, the snowfall averages 300 to 500 inches each year. During the winter of 1951 to 52 snow levels were measured at 65 feet near Donner Summit.</string>
    <string name="loggingcomstock">The 1960 Winter Olympics was a winter multi-sport event held between February 18–28, 1960 in Squaw Valley, California, United States. Squaw Valley was chosen to host the Games at the 1956 meeting of the International Olympic Committee (IOC). It was an undeveloped resort in 1955, so from 1956 to 1960 the infrastructure and all of the venues were built at a cost of US$80,000,000. It was designed to be intimate, allowing spectators and competitors to walk to nearly all the venues. Squaw Valley hosted athletes from thirty nations who competed in four sports and twenty-seven events. Women\'s speed skating and biathlon made their Olympic debuts. The organizers decided the bobsled events did not warrant the cost to build a venue, so for the first and only time bobsled was not on the Winter Olympic program. The Soviet Union dominated the medal count winning twenty-one medals, seven of which were gold. Soviet speed skaters Yevgeny Grishin and Lidiya Skoblikova won two gold medals each. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1960_Winter_Olympics</string>
    <string name="mountainchickadee">The most common bird in the Tahoe Basin is the Mountain Chickadee. These small plump birds have a black cap, black bib under their chin and a white line over each eye. Active and acrobatic, clinging to small limbs and twigs or hanging upside down from pine cones. In winter, Mountain Chickadees flock with kinglets and nuthatches, with birds following each other one by one from tree to tree. \n\n Source\n https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Mountain_Chickadee/id</string>
    <string name="mountainion">The mountain lion is also known as cougar, panther, or puma. Body coloration can range from tan to gray and cubs are usually covered with blackish brown spots. Adult range from 7 to 8 feet long (from the tip of the nose to the tip of the tail), and can weigh between 65 and 150 pounds.</string>
    <string name="mttallac">Mt. Tallac at 9,735 feet is the highest peak rising from the shoreline. The highest point in the Tahoe Basin is Freel Peak at 10,881 feet. Lake Tahoe is the third deepest lake in North America and the tenth deepest in the world. (Lake Baikal, in Russia, is the deepest at over 4,600 feet.) Tahoe\'s deepest point is 1,645 feet near Crystal Bay. The average depth of Lake Tahoe is 989 feet. The Lake\'s surface is 6,226.95 feet above sea level and the natural rim is 6,223 feet above sea level, making it the highest lake of its size in the United States.</string>
    <string name="nativeamerica">Lake Tahoe was occupied only by Native American tribes. Artifacts confirm the presence of the Washoe Tribe of Native Americans at Lake Tahoe over 10,000 years ago. The Wašiw people are a distinct people who share commonalities with both the Great Basin and the California Cultures. For many thousands of years, Large Cutthroat Trout lived in all the lakes and streams along with freshwater clams and other fish once plentiful, sustained the people throughout the year. Large and small game was once plentiful. Plant gathering for food, utilitarian and medicinal use is still harvested in all parts of Wašiw lands. During the fall the Wašiw traveled to the pine nut hills to gather pinion nuts or to the western slope of the Sierras to gather acorns. The fall was also time for hunting. During the winters the Wašiw would travel to lowland valleys where the harsh winter snows felt by the Sierra Mountains would be bearable. When the snows started melting, it was a time for renewal and it was time to begin the cycle of life again. Wašiw has been classified as a distinct branch of the Hokan language family known as Washoan. Although, the language is considered to be a language isolate by many. The uniqueness Wašiw language is directly related to the uniqueness of the Wašiw homeland. The name Tahoe comes from a mispronunciation of the Washoe Native American name for Lake Tahoe, “da ow a ga”, which means edge of the lake. Lake Tahoe was in relative seclusion until General John C. Fremont\'s exploration party discovered the lake in 1844. \n\n Source\n\nhttps://www.washoetribe.us/contents/</string>
    <string name="northenGoshawk">The Northern Goshawk is a raptor that lives in forests and preys on rodents and birds. Goshawks have long been a part of the Lake Tahoe Basin ecosystem. They live at the lake year-round and breed from lake level to tree line. The Northern goshawk is listed by the California Board of Forestry as a sensitive species in the California Forest Practice Rules, and is currently listed as a sensitive species by the US Forest Service. Coloring includes some white or cinnamon streaks and white spots. Tail dark brown with jagged dark bars. Underparts are whitish with broad dark brown streaks. Pale eyebrow stripes are usually visible on a brown head. \n\n Source\n https://www.audubon.org/field-guide/bird/northern-goshawk</string>
    <string name="oregonjunco">the Oregon Junco is one of the most abundant and easily recognized birds in the Sierra forest. These small birds have solid black heads and white stripes on either side of their tails and are often seen eating seeds on the forest floor.</string>
    <string name="ponderosaPine">Ponderosa Pine *P. ponderosa is a large coniferous pine (evergreen) tree, nicknamed “Prickly Ponderosa”. The Ponderosa has a yellowish tan bark and forms large plates between shallow furrows. Cones are 3” to 5” long with outward turned prickles on each scales. Limbs are short and tips turn upward with tufts of needles. Ponderosa Pine grows and appears similar to Jeffrey Pines in most ways, except it is found as lower elevations, below 7,000 feet commonly, and has prickly cones. Ponderosa pine prefers somewhat lower elevations as the consume vast amounts of water. you can find many of these species in Emerald Bay State Park. The National Register of Big Trees lists a ponderosa pine that is 235 ft (72 m) tall and 324 in (820 cm) in circumference. In January 2011, a Pacific ponderosa pine in the Rogue River–Siskiyou National Forest in Oregon was measured with a laser to b e 268.35 ft (81.79 m) high. One can easily identify some trees by smelling their bark. Ponderosa Pine bark smells like vanilla or butterscotch. Large trees live for 500 or more years. \n\n Source\n http://www.nps.gov/brca/learn/nature/ponderosapine.htm</string>
    <string name="porcupine">The Porcupine is the largest member of the rodent family. When alarmed it turns a way, erects the quills, humps the body, and swings its stout tail. If any quills touch an inquiring dog, wildcat, or person, the barbed tips lodge in the enemy\'s skin. The Porcupine is active mainly at night, when it feeds on the succulent inner bark of conifers.</string>
    <string name="redTailHawk">A large heavy set hawk with broad wings, the adult Red-Tailed Hawk is dark brown above and light below with a reddish tail. These hawks habitually soar in wide circles and can easily be seen on clear days, seemingly to enjoy the view, when actually they are hunting for rats, mice, rabbits, or an occasional small reptile. \n\n Source\n https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Red-tailed_Hawk/id</string>
    <string name="robin">The Robin is a summer visitor in the Lake Tahoe Basin, appearing soon after the snow melts. Its brick-red breast, yellow bill and gray back makes identification easy. It is a very common bird, frequently observed hopping across lawns or small openings in the forest searching for worms and insects. \n\n Source\n https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_robin</string>
    <string name="sssTahoe">The S.S. TAHOE was a steam ship that launched on Lake Tahoe on August 26, 1896. She was the largest of the lake steamers at 169 feet in length. The steamer was propelled by two wood-fired engines developing a total of 1200 hp, each driving a three-bladed propeller. Her 200 passengers enjoyed a well-appointed interior, with leather upholstery, carpeting, and marble fixtures in the lavatories. The S.S. TAHOE was scuttled in 1940. The wreck presently lies in 400 feet of water off Glenbrook, Nevada. The wreck was first visited in 2002 by a record-setting high-altitude dive, and as a result became the first maritime site in Nevada to be listed in the National Register of Historic Places.</string>
    <string name="stellerJay">Almost anyone who spends time in the forest will meet the noisy Steller\'s Jay. This pigeon-sized bird with deep blue wings, tail, and breast, is hard to miss. Often this jay becomes quite bold, sometimes stealing bread crusts from tables where people are picnicking</string>
    <string name="sugarPine">Pinus lambertiana (commonly known as the sugar pine or sugar cone pine) is the tallest and most massive pine tree, and has the longest cones of any conifer, 12” to 18” in length. At one time, Sugar pines once comprised a quarter of Lake Tahoe’s forests, Today they are rare in the basin and make up less than 5% of the forest composition, however you might be able to find one near Vikingsholm or along the Rubicon Trails at Emerald Bay State Park. The sugar pine is the largest species of pine, commonly growing to 40–60 meters (130–200 ft) tall, exceptionally up to 82 m (269 ft) tall, with a trunk diameter of 1.5–2.5 m (4.9–8.2 ft), exceptionally 3.5 m (11 ft). Tallest recorded specimen is one standing at 83.45 m (273.79 ft) in Yosemite National Park, discovered in 2015. The folks at the Sugar Pine Foundation are dedicated to saving Lake Tahoe\'s sugar pines and other white pines from blister rust by educating and involving the local community in hands-on forest stewardship. Since 2008, they have planted over 70,000 trees with local students and community members. \n\n Source\n http://www.sugarpinefoundation.org https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pinus_lambertiana#/media/File:Sugarpine.jpg http://www.na.fs.fed.us/pubs/silvics_manual/Volume_1/pinus/lambertiana.htm</string>
    <string name="tsunami">There are three major fault lines running across the bottom of Lake Tahoe. In the event of major quake, portions of the lake floor may shift physically and cause a massive, underwater landslide. Water displaced by the slide can generate a powerful tsunami wave. Scientists developed a computer model that takes into account the steep, underwater banks on the west shore near one of the larger fault lines. The study shows that a 7.1-magnitude trembler could trigger a tidal wave that would race northeast across the lake\'s surface and possibly inundate the beaches and lakeside homes along the North Shore from Carnelian Bay to Incline Village. Geologists believe that four-mile segment of the West Shore collapsed into the Lake 15 thousand years ago.. This cataclysmic event caused a massive submerged debris avalanche, which produced a 300-foot high tsunami and widened the Lake by three miles. The slide event was presumably triggered by an earthquake. \n\n Source\nhttps://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bxbVEnnmRGQ</string>
    <string name="vikingsholm">Vikingsholm is located at the head of Emerald Bay in Lake Tahoe, California. This magnificent castle is a unique blend of Nature\'s spectacular beauty and man\'s architectural ingenuity. Vikingsholm, situated majestically among towering pines and cedars, was built as a summer home by Mrs. Lora Josephine Knight in 1929. Vikingsholm is one of the finest examples of Scandinavian architecture in the western hemisphere. Mrs. Lora Josephine Knight purchased the property encompassing the head of Emerald Bay and Fannette Island in 1928 for $250,000. Two hundred workers were brought to Emerald Bay and started hand hewing the timbers, carving the intricate designs, hand planing the wood for the interior walls, and forging the hinges and latches. Most of the materials to construct the home came from the Tahoe Basin. \n\n Source\n http://www.vikingsholm.com</string>
    <string name="westernTanger">The male Western Tanager is one of the most colorful birds in the Lake Tahoe Basin. His red head, bright yellow body with black on the back, wings, and tail, makes him a very eye-catching bird. Females and immatures are a somewhat dimmer yellow-green and blackish. These birds live in open woods all over the West, particularly among evergreens, where they often stay hidden in the canopy. \n\n Source\n https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Western_Tanager/id</string>
    <string name="yellowBelliedMarrmot">The yellow bellied marmot, also known as the rock chuck, is a ground squirrel. You may hear a strange chuck whistle or trill at the top of one of Tahoe’s rocky peaks or high elevation meadows and soon realize that it is coming from the yellow-bellied marmot. Adult males typically weigh between 6.0 to 11.0 lb females typically weigh between 3.5 to 9.0 lb. They have a brown coat, a white patch of fur between the eyes, a reddish-brown tail, and a yellow belly, from which they get their name. Litters usually average three to five offspring per female. Only about half of those pups survive and become yearlings. Yellow-bellied marmots spend about 80 percent of their life in their burrow, 60 percent of which is spent hibernating. They often spend mid-day and night in a burrow as well. These burrows are usually constructed on a slope, such as a hill, mountain, or cliff. The hibernation burrows can be up to 16 to 23 ft deep, but the burrows constructed for daily use are usually only 3 ft deep. \n\n Source\n https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yellow-bellied_marmot</string>
    <string name="yellowHeadedBlackbird">Yellow-Headed Blackbird is often found in cattail and tule marshes. No other Lake Tahoe Basin bird has such a distinctive yellow head and black body. It is generally spotted in the Pope Marsh area during early spring. \n\n Source\n https://www.allaboutbirds.org/guide/Yellow-headed_Blackbird/id</string>
</resources>